<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian Plancher</title>
    <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brian Plancher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://plancherb1.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of Approximate Matrix Multiplication to Neural Networks and Distributed SLAM</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/appliedapproxmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/appliedapproxmm/</guid>
      <description>We apply approximate matrix multiplication to artificial Neural Networks for image classification and to the robotics problem of Distributed Simultaneous Localization and Mapping increasing the speed of both applications by 15-20% while maintaining a 97% classification accuracy for NNs running on the MNIST dataset and keeping the average robot position error under 1 meter (vs 0.32 meters for the exact solution). However, both applications experience variance in their results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Compute in Autonomous Aerial Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/roleofcompute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/roleofcompute/</guid>
      <description>By combining MAVBench (our tool-set, which consists of (1) a closed-loop real-time feedback simulator and (2) an end-to-end benchmark suite comprised of state-of-the-art kernels), analytical modeling, and an understanding of various compute impacts, we show up to 2X and 1.8X improvements for mission time and mission energy for two optimization case studies. Our investigations, as well as our optimizations, show that cyber-physical co-design, a methodology with which both the cyber and physical processes/quantities of the robot are developed with consideration of one another, similar to hardware-software co-design, is necessary for arriving at the design of the optimal robot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Model Predictive Control using Parallel DDP on a GPU</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/parallelddp_icra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/parallelddp_icra/</guid>
      <description>In this extended abstract we extend our previous work by using our Parallel DDP implementation for MPC on a physical Kuka arm. We demonstrated the feasibility of this approach in the presence of model discrepancies and communication delays between the robot and GPU and found that higher control rates generally lead to better tracking performance across a range of parallelization options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Performance Analysis of Parallel Differential Dynamic Programming on a GPU</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/parallelddp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/parallelddp/</guid>
      <description>We analyze the benefits and tradeoffs of higher degrees of parallelization using a multiple-shooting variant of DDP implemented on a GPU. We describe our implementation strategy and present results demonstrating its performance compared to an equivalent multi-threaded CPU implementation using several benchmark control tasks. Our results suggest that GPU-based solvers can offer increased per-iteration computation time and faster convergence in some cases, but in general tradeoffs exist between convergence behavior and degree of algorithm-level parallelism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel and Constrained Differential Dynamic Programming for Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/mastersthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/mastersthesis/</guid>
      <description>This thesis builds on recent work on Unscented Dynamic Programming (UDP)—which eliminates dynamics derivative computations in DDP—to support general nonlinear state and input constraints to high precision using an augmented Lagrangian. It then leverages parallel computations for increased throughput and systematically analyzes the insights, challenges, tradeoffs, and benefits of implementing a parallelized variant of DDP on both a multi-core CPU and a graphics processing unit (GPU).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constrained Unscented Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/cudp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/cudp/</guid>
      <description>We build on recent work on Unscented Dynamic Programming (UDP) - which eliminates dynamics derivative computations in DDP - to support general nonlinear state and input constraints using an augmented Lagrangian. The resulting algorithm has the same computational cost as first-order penalty-based DDP variants, but can achieve constraint satisfaction to high precision without the numerical ill-conditioning associated with penalty methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-based, collaborative, algorithmic robotics for high school students: Programming self-driving race cars at MIT</title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/racecarteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/publication/racecarteaching/</guid>
      <description>We describe the pedagogy behind the MIT Beaver Works Summer Institute Robotics Program, a new high-school STEM program in robotics. The program utilizes state-of-the-art sensors and embedded computers for mobile robotics. The program was offered as a four-week residential program at MIT in the summer of 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://plancherb1.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://plancherb1.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student studying Robotics and Controls at Harvard University working with Vijay Janapa Reddi and Scott Kuindersma. My research is focused on developing and implementing algorithms for realtime model predictive control for complex high dimensional robots by exploiting both the mathematical structure of algorithms and the design of computational platforms. As such my research spans Robotics, Controls, and Computer Architecture. I have a passion for teaching and enjoy spending my free time with my wife and puppy and ski racing in the winters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>